A Guide to the Commonwealth Fund records, Video Recordings, SG 1, Series 39 FA1286
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund records, Video Recordings, SG 1, Series 39
1986-2002
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund
FA1286
72 tapes 72 videotapes.
Conditions Governing Access
Records are open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
Arrangement
As received.
Scope and Contents
This series contains video records from the Commonwealth Fund archives.
Moving Images
- Commonwealth Fund records, Video Recordings, 1986-2002; 39
  - Breaking The Cycle, Sound, 30 minutes; VHS videocassette (Box 1, Tape AV 10827)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Access copy available.
  - Public Benefits Outreach "Changing Lives", Sound, 8 minutes; VHS videocassette (Box 1, Tape AV 10828)
  - Picker-Commonwelth Project - Excerpts from Focus Groups with Members of the Upstate HMOs, 1992 March; Sound, 12 minutes; VHS videocassette (Box 1, Tape AV 10829)
  - Through the Patient's Eye, VHS videocassette (Box 1, Tape AV 10830)
  - Give With Confidence, VHS videocassette (Box 1, Tape AV 10831)
  - Give With Confidence, VHS videocassette (Box 1, Tape AV 10832)
  - Public Benefits Outreach Project, Sound, 14 minutes; VHS videocassette (Box 1, Tape AV 10833)
  - 4000 Foundations - The People and the Money, VHS videocassette (Box 1, Tape AV 10834)
  - Segment on Sponsor a Scholar program home, VHS videocassette (Box 1, Tape AV 10835)
  - Courage to Care, Sound, 29 minutes; VHS videocassette (Box 1, Tape AV 10836)
  - The Giraffe Project - It's Up to Us, VHS videocassette (Box 1, Tape AV 10837)
  - Surveying the Restraint-free Facility, Sound, 14 minutes; VHS videocassette (Box 2, Tape AV 10838)
  - The Family Guide to Restraint-free Care, Sound, 12 minutes; VHS videocassette (Box 2, Tape AV 10839)
  - Working With Residents Who Wander, 1995 May 5; Sound, 13 minutes; VHS videocassette (Box 2, Tape AV 10840)
  - The Family, VHS videocassette (Box 2, Tape AV 10841)
  - Up and About - Minimizing the Risk of Fall Injuries, 1995 May 5; Sound, 15 minutes; VHS videocassette (Box 2, Tape AV 10842)
  - Up and About - Minimizing the Risk of Fall Injuries, 1995 February 3; VHS videocassette (Box 2, Tape AV 10843)
  - Training Video - Healthy Steps, VHS videocassette (Box 2, Tape AV 10844)
  - Wild in the Streets, Sound, 50 minutes; VHS videocassette (Box 2, Tape AV 10845)
  - Street Stories - The Massachusetts Saving Lives Program, Sound, 15 minutes; VHS videocassette (Box 2, Tape AV 10846)
  - The New Resident, 1995 June 8; VHS videocassette (Box 2, Tape AV 10847)
  - Working With Residents Who Wander, Sound, 13 minutes; VHS videocassette (Box 3, Tape AV 10848)
  - For Families Quality Care Without Restraints, VHS videocassette (Box 3, Tape AV 10849)
  - For Families - Questions and Answers About Restraints, 1994 February 8; VHS videocassette (Box 3, Tape AV 10850)
  - Setting the Stage, 1994 March 2; VHS videocassette (Box 3, Tape AV 10851)
  - The New Resident, 1994 March 4; VHS videocassette (Box 3, Tape AV 10852)
  - The Management Perspective, Sound, 17 minutes; VHS videocassette (Box 3, Tape AV 10853)
  - Staying Restraint Free Evenings, Nights and Weekends, Sound, 13 minutes; VHS videocassette (Box 3, Tape AV 10854)
  - Staying Restraint Free Evenings, Nights and Weekends, Sound, 13 minutes; VHS videocassette (Box 3, Tape AV 10855)
  - Getting Hit, Grabbed, and Threatened - What it Means and What to Do, Sound, 15 minutes; VHS videocassette (Box 3, Tape AV 10856)
  - Getting Hit, Grabbed, and Threatened - What it Means and What to Do, 1995 February 3; VHS videocassette (Box 3, Tape AV 10857)
  - The Management Perspective, Sound, 15 minutes; VHS videocassette (Box 4, Tape AV 10858)
  - Healthy Steps CD Rom Video Vignettes, Sound, 60 minutes; VHS videocassette (Box 4, Tape AV 10859)
  - Healthy Steps - Teachable Moments and Supporting Families, Sound, 41 minutes; VHS videocassette (Box 4, Tape AV 10860)
  - Now That the Restraints Are Off, What Do We Do?, Sound, 13 minutes; VHS videocassette (Box 4, Tape AV 10861)
  - Now That the Restraints Are Off, What Do We Do?, VHS videocassette (Box 4, Tape AV 10862)
  - Everyone Wins Module 1 - The New Resident, 1995; Sound, 13 minutes; VHS videocassette (Box 4, Tape AV 10863)
  - Everyone Wins Module 2 - Up and About - Minimizing the Risk of Fall Injuries, 1995; Sound, 15 minutes; VHS videocassette (Box 4, Tape AV 10864)
  - Everyone Wins Module 3 - Working With Residents Who Wander, 1995; Sound, 13 minutes; VHS videocassette (Box 4, Tape AV 10865)
  - Everyone Wins Module 4 - Getting Hit, Grabbed, and Threatened: What It Means, What To Do, 1995; Sound, 15 minutes; VHS videocassette (Box 4, Tape AV 10866)
  - Everyone Wins Module 5 - Staying Restraint-Free Evenings, Nights, and Weekends, 1995; Sound, 13 minutes; VHS videocassette (Box 4, Tape AV 10867)
  - Everyone Wins Module 6 - Now That the Restraints Are Off, What Do We Do?, 1995; Sound, 13 minutes; VHS videocassette (Box 5, Tape AV 10868)
  - The Jewish Home and Hospital for Aged in New York City, Sound, 40 minutes; VHS videocassette (Box 5, Tape AV 10869)
  - Johns Hopkins Hospital Youth Mentoring Program, VHS videocassette (Box 5, Tape AV 10870)
  - Patients and Doctors Who Are Partners, Sound, 28 minutes; VHS videocassette (Box 5, Tape AV 10871)
  - Breast Cancer Surgery Decision Shared Decision-Making Program, Sound, 67 minutes; VHS videocassette (Box 5, Tape AV 10872)
  - HRT Interviews, VHS videocassette (Box 5, Tape AV 10873)
  - MGH HRT Interviews, 1994 June 1; Sound, 20 minutes; VHS videocassette (Box 5, Tape AV 10874)
  - Marlborough Saving Lives Program, 1989 July; VHS videocassette (Box 5, Tape AV 10875)
  - Medford Saving Lives, VHS videocassette (Box 5, Tape AV 10876)
  - Keeping the Promise, 1989 December; Sound, 16 minutes; VHS videocassette (Box 5, Tape AV 10877)
  - Outward Bound, VHS videocassette (Box 6, Tape AV 10878)
  - If I Don't Live to Be Tomorrow - Hospital Care for People with AIDS, 1986; VHS; Sound, Color, 39 minutes (Box 6, Tape AV 10879)
    Scope and Contents
    Program includes interviews with New York City health care workers about tending to AIDS patients. Also includes interviews with AIDS patients describing their experiences within the hospital system. A Presentation of the New York City Health and Hospitals Corporation. Narrated by Colleen Dewhurst.
  - Single-First Time Buyers- Low Income (Group I), VHS videocassette (Box 6, Tape AV 10880)
  - Married- Parents- Low Income (Group II), VHS videocassette (Box 6, Tape AV 10881)
  - Health Care - Chronic, VHS videocassette (Box 6, Tape AV 10882)
  - NCQA at PhilaFocus, 1994 May 9; VHS videocassette (Box 6, Tape AV 10883)
  - NCQA at PhilaFocus, 1994 May 9; VHS videocassette (Box 6, Tape AV 10884)
  - HealthCare - Retired, VHS videocassette (Box 6, Tape AV 10885)
  - United Hospital Fund Report, Sound, 4 minutes; VHS videocassette (Box 6, Tape AV 10886)
  - Partnership for a Drug Free America Press Conference, VHS videocassette (Box 6, Tape AV 10887)
  - Milestones in Mentoring, 1990; Sound, 2 hours; VHS videocassette (Box 6, Tape AV 10888)
  - Michigan Global Citizenship, Sound, 13 minutes; VHS videocassette (Box 7, Tape AV 10889)
  - Global Citizenship Program, 1992 January; Sound, 13 minutes; VHS videocassette (Box 7, Tape AV 10890)
  - Close to Home Elder Abuse - Intervention Strategies for Clinicians, 1992; Sound, 19 minutes; VHS videocassette (Box 7, Tape AV 10891)
  - Inner City Grade School, 1994 July; VHS videocassette (Box 7, Tape AV 10892)
  - Inner City Press Conference, 1994 September; VHS videocassette (Box 7, Tape AV 10893)
  - Health in our Hands, VHS videocassette (Box 7, Tape AV 10894)
  - An American Hero: The Story of Congressman John Lewis, 2002; VHS videocassette; Sound, black and white/color, 15 minutes (Box 7, Tape AV 10895)
    Written and directed by Raymond D. Strother, narrated by Brock Peters, with songs by Bettie Mae Fikes.
    John Robert Lewis was an American politician and civil rights activist who served in the United States House of Representatives for Georgia's 5th congressional district from 1987 until his death in 2020. He was the chairman of the Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee from 1963 to 1966.
    In this video, Lewis discusses his association with Dr. Martin Luther King Jr., the use of nonviolent activism in sit-ins, at the March on Selma, and in regard to specific events, such as the 1963 Birmingham Church bombing. Includes a brief interview with wife Lillian Lewis and a 2000 speech by President Bill Clinton.
  - Worlds Apart - Phillips Story, VHS videocassette (Box 7, Tape AV 10896)
  - 341 Summit Version, Sound, 13 minutes; VHS videocassette (Box 7, Tape AV 10897)
  - ACMI Morris Collen Video, Sound, 17 minutes; VHS videocassette (Box 7, Tape AV 10898)